Brother, I am troubled. Something is
wrong, and I do not know if the
wrongness lies within the world or
within myself. Speak your feelings,
brother. If there's any way to help you,
I will. We are strong, brother, are we
not?
>> Yes, brother. The mightiest bulls in the
prairie. Yes, and we are enormous. Is
that right? Indeed. Our girth cannot be
denied. Brother, we rule over this
prairie unchallenged. Do we not,
brother? Our powers uncontested. Ours
are the heers and ours the greatest
grass from one side of the great fence
to the other. Why, brother? What
troubles you? And we have many calves,
do we not? Dosens, brother. Then where
are they, brother? Where? We both have
calves, sons and daughters. But have you
seen them lately? Of course, brother.
They are in the herd. Where in the herd,
brother? Do you see them? I can hardly
be expected to keep track of every calf
in the herd, brother. Do you see any of
them? Even one? Why yes, I see your son,
Linis, over in the barn.
>> Hello.
>> Yes, and there is something wrong with
Dennis, isn't there?
>> I cannot fathom what you mean, brother.
>> Lovely weather here in the barn. The
tall, skinny ones. They've done
something to him, brother.
>> No, now you sound like the pigs. So, you
have heard them speaking, too. Pigs are
fools, brother. Always concerned with
getting more food in their bellies. Do
you see us starving? No, brother. We
want for nothing. If anything, the tall,
skinny ones they worship serve us. I do
not think that is how they see it,
brother. Then they must surely fear us.
Why? We could crush them. Yes. And gore
them with our horns. Our mighty horns.
And then stomp their bones with our
hooves until they crack indeed. And
crush the very breath of life from their
flesh and drag them out for the pigs to
devour. That we could bother. But why
might we? Do you see the shed in the
distance between the house and the barn?
Why don't bother looking past the great
things, brother? Our kingdom is here.
All we want is here. Our he, our grass.
There isn't any point looking farther.
But you do see it. I can look upon it if
it troubles you. So the pigs call it.
You speak of the pigs again, brother.
You have become obsessed with those
filthy creatures. They call it the shed
of no return. Oh, how ominous. But your
calf Dennis did return.
>> I think I see a merge.
>> Things are fools. Yes, they took Dennis
to that shed and he returns damaged.
They have done something to him,
brother. If you insist. You don't care,
do you, brother? You would rather ignore
the truth right in front of you than
admit something evil is being done to
us. To our calves. We have other calves.
I don't see any. And we can make as many
more as we want. Listen to yourself,
brother. All you care about is your
grass, your heers. You see nothing else.
There is nothing else to see, brother.
That is all the joy in the world. Seeing
the rest brings sadness. You know more
than you are saying. And if you do not
wish to have more sadness, you will look
less and know less and say less than do
I.
Dennis won't be able to sire any calves,
will he? Of course not, brother. He
would challenge our rule. And when we
are too old to sire, the tall, steady
ones will bring in new bulls then. So
our dynasty is meaningless. It dies with
us, brother. And our other calves, our
sons and daughters, some for meat and
some for milk, if what the crows say is
true. And of pigs. Yes, brother. fools
all of them to know so much. Better not
to better by far.
I could break the great fence. I am
strong enough. And then what, brother? I
could charge through the door of the
house. Break it down with my hooves. The
older one sleeps in there at night. I
could stomp him into the hay of his
bedding before he can reach the loud
stick. There are more of the tall,
skinny ones that tin to the hay bells.
They have sharp sticks, brother, and
they sleep near them in the barn.
>> It's cold in here.
>> I could gore them, charge at them from
behind. Both of them, brother. At the
same time, they will skewer you with old
sticks, and you will be no more. I
could. If you helped me, brother. And
what then? If you did, more would come.
With the sun, the others would arrive on
the great metal beast and see their
fellows dead. And you and I painted in
their gore, and they would take their
sharp sticks and a loud stick, and we
would feed the pigs. Well, indeed,
brother, then we will leave before the
sun rises. And then what? We lead all
heers into the wilderness to be hunted
by predators. But all skinny ones will
find us. They will take us back. Not if
we kill them, too. Can you kill all of
them, brother? Can you murder the world?
Can you bathe your mighty horns in the
blood of a dozen? A dozen dozen with
horses and metal beasts and sharp sticks
and loud sticks and all of the
malevolence of a runged father and all
of the rapacity of a ravenous pig. No,
but I can kill more of them with you at
my side, brother. Then the whole herd
dies. Our rule, our pasture. We lose
everything, brother. For nothing. For
vengeance, brother. You
You have slept here before in the cool
grass. Sleep tonight, brother. We have
forgotten a multitude of sorrows here.
Life is better than revenge. Sleep
beside me as you have before, brother.
The doom of the morning will cool your
blood, and tomorrow's thoughts will be
clearer than tonight's.
No.
No dreams will not come near me this
night, brother, for my eyes are swollen
red and will not shut, and my thoughts
are blood. I am going, brother. I will
break down the great fence, and the herd
will leave with you or without you. I am
going to the house, and before I die, I
will feel the flesh of the tall, skinny
ones on my hooves. I will feel the air
go out of their lungs. I will feel their
bodies cold upon the ground before I
join them.
Then it ends tonight, brother. Alone or
together, brother. It ends side by side
then until the death of the world.